# Simu Liu

## Full Stack Developer

🔀 simuliu711@gmail.com 💡 Montreal, QC, Canada 🌘 apple0441

### **Profile**

Full Stack Developer with 7+ years of experience specializing in React and React Native development. He has created a wide range of apps, including diabetes tracking, event booking and ticketing, and budgeting. Simu Liu works in a clear and organized manner, ensuring that projects are well-planned before he starts programming. He contributes exceptional value as projects progress from start to finish while adding new features to existing products.

## **Professional Experience**

#### Full Stack Developer, Trigent

03/2021 - 05/2023 | Remote

- Created a web application that allowed 75K users to search for nearby restaurants based on their location with 89% accuracy.
- Worked with a team of 27 developers that created an e-commerce website using PHP, MySQL, and JavaScript within 3 months.
- Developed a responsive email template in HTML5 and CSS3 that oncreased the clickthrough rate by 78%, an improvement from previous years.
- Participated in code reviews of 100 developers' ensuring that all code complied 100% with coding standards & best practices.

#### **Full Stack Developer,** Webcrafters

02/2018 - 02/2021 | Warszawa, Poland

- Developed a brand new administration panel for purchasing agent business, which increased the customer service by 90% and improved the efficiency of operating by over 25%
- Increased customer satisfaction to 85% by creating database utilizing {H{5, PDO, and MySQL that streamlined tracking operations from creating, assigning and tracking truckloads.
- Developed 25 original e-commerce website and web applications, encompassing design, coding, testing and maintenance whilst supervising a team of 15 web developers.

#### Junior Web Developer, TapInfluence

12/2015 - 01/2018

Mountain View, United States

- Created a new landing page system which used a PostgreSQL database and an s3 bucket to drive the images and links for quick searches on the platform.
- Collaborated the routing system on the search platform using react-router so that all searches were URL driven, allowing for saved and quick navigation.
- Built a simple user interface for use by the data science team to test out their new features without using URL or Postman.
- Extended internal data science tool to a separate, customer-facing platform for creating smaller, less focused influencer marketing campaigns using React, React-Apollo, and GraphQL.
- Learned React and Redux to work on the new search platform concept, the first foray into using React on the platform.

## **Education**

### **Bachelor of Computer Science,**

Hong Kong University of Science and Technology(HKUST) ☑

09/2012 - 11/2015 | Kowloon, Hong Kong

 $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\bullet$ 

## **Skills**

English

MERN MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js	••••	<b>MEAN</b> MongoDB, Express.js, Angular.js, Node.js	• • • •
<b>MEVN</b> MongoDB, Express.js, Vue.js, Node.js	• • • •	<b>Django</b> (HTML, CSS, JS/TS, python)	• • • •
LAMP Linux, Apache, MySQL ,PHP/Python/Perl	••••	<b>Database</b> MySQL, Oracle, MongoDB, NoSQL	• • • •
WordPress	••••	<b>Cloud</b> Firebase, Cloudflare, AWS	••••
Languages			

Chinese